

# Muhammad Aamir

Date of birth: 04/08/1994

Nationality: Pakistani

Gender: Male

### CONTACT

Hartmannstraße, 129 91058 Erlangen, Germany

muhammad.aamir@fau.de
muhammad.aamir.cs94@gmail.c

om

(+49) 15218876575

(+49) 17666889673

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/</a>

muhammad-aamir-677719135

### **ABOUT ME**

I am pursuing my Masters in Computational Engineering at University of Erlangen Nuremberg Germany with the focus in the Deep Learning domain. Beside studies, I am working in Siemens Healthineers AG in the field of Image processing, specializing in particular on developing deep learning techniques for inverse problems in low-level computer vision.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

04/01/2021 - CURRENT - Erlangen, Germany

## Working Student (Data scientist)

Siemens Healthineers

- I am working in the field of Image Processing, Specializing in particular on deep learning based methods (with focus on Convolutional Neural Networks) for inverse problems in low level Computer Vision.
- I mainly investigate the comparison of traditionally model based denoising methods and deep learning-based methods for flexible, effective, efficient and interpretable image restoration.

## 23/03/2020 - 31/10/2020 - Erlangen, Germany

# Working Student (Data Analyst)

Siemens Healthineers

- Data pre-processing, Data Wrangling, Data Analysis on Medical Dicom Images including CT Scans, X-rays.
- Selection & Evaluation of different Al Algorithms to perform standard qualitative and quantitative measurements evaluation
- Validation by benchmarking ground truth of existing data/reports

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

**01/10/2019 – CURRENT** – Schloßplatz 4, 91054 Erlangen, Erlangen, Germany

MSc. Computational Engineering (In process)

University of Erlangen-Nuremberg (Friedrich-Alexander-Universität )

https://www.fau.de/

**01/09/2015 – 01/08/2019** – 13 National Stadium Rd, Karsaz Faisal Cantonment, Karachi City, Sindh, Pakistan, Karachi, Pakistan

Bachelor of Computer Science

Bahria University Karachi Pakistan

https://www.bahria.edu.pk/

# **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## My Digital Skills

programming (C++, Python, C#) / Framework : Pytorch, Tensorflow / Visual Studio, Anaconda platform, Jupyter Notebook / Databases : SQL Server, Oracle 12C / MS Office (MS Word, MS Excel and MS Powerpoint) / Matlab

## **PROJECTS**

## 01/08/2018 - 31/03/2019

Classification of Musculoskeletal Radiographs Using Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN's)

 $^{\circ}$  Worked on the dataset of about 40,000 images provided by the Stanford University Hospital.

 Developed an intelligent system based on convolutional neural network which detect bone abnormality by examining x-ray images.

### 01/09/2017 - 01/03/2018

## Driving License Management System, OLTP & DWH (Oracle 12C, C#)

- GUI development for Driving License Management System
- Use of MS PowerPoint for Presentation and MS Excel for Structuring data in a Normalized Form

## HONOURS AND AWARDS

### 01/04/2018

Monetary Merit Scholarship Award Holder - Bahria University Karachi Pakistan

#### 04/10/2021

**Completion of Deep Learning Exercises with 100% Unit Test Coverage** – University of Erlangen-Nuremberg (Friedrich-Alexander-Universität)

 Completed the Deep learning coursework exercises based on the core deep learning methods including CNN's, RNN and the understanding of Pytorch framework

https://gitlab.cs.fau.de/py53gufo/awards-and-certifications/-/blob/main/Aamir Muhammad Certificate DL .pdf

#### 01/05/2019

What is Data Science - IBM

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/WFSA5MRAWFVF

#### 11/05/2019

Data Science Ethics – University of Michigan

https://gitlab.cs.fau.de/py53gufo/awards-and-certifications/-/blob/main/Data\_Ethics\_Certificate.pdf

#### 06/09/2017

Introduction to Data Storage and Management Technologies – IEEE

https://gitlab.cs.fau.de/py53gufo/awards-and-certifications/-/blob/main/IEEE Certificate.pdf

## COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

The International English Language Testing System (IELTS)

Overall Test Score 6.5 with CEFR Level B2

https://gitlab.cs.fau.de/py53gufo/awards-and-certifications/-/blob/main/IELTS\_CERTIFICATION.pdf

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Urdu

**OTHER LANGUAGE(S):** 

**English** 

<b>Listening</b>	<b>Reading</b>	<b>Spoken production</b>	<b>Spoken interaction</b>	<b>Writing</b>
B2	B1	B2	B2	B2
German  Listening  A1	<b>Reading</b> A2	<b>Spoken production</b> A2	<b>Spoken interaction</b> A1	<b>Writing</b> A2